Finding Aid for Carnegie Corporation of New York. Aging Society Project (1982-1986) records
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Carnegie Corporation of New York. Aging Society Project (1982-1986) records
Carnegie Corporation of New York. Aging Society Project (1982-1986)
8819 Bs 2
Project established to study the public policy implications of an aging society. Administrative files, largely of project director D. Lydia Bronte, including subject files, name files, publication records, and conference files.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
19 linear feet
This record group forms part of the Michigan Historical Collection / Institute of Gerontology Joint Archives in Gerontology (donor no. 6160 )
The record group is open to research.
The Aging Society Project was an inquiry into the public policy implications of an aging society. It originated in the Spring of 1982, when Alan Pifer, the outgoing president of the Carnegie Corporation, began to explore the significance of demographic changes in the United States during the previous thirty years. He commissioned two preliminary studies, by Michael Teitelbaum and D. Lydia Bronte, which pointed to the need for a more thorough study on the issues of aging.
In December 1982, the Carnegie Corporation approved funding for a one-year planning phase for the Aging Project, which was to be chaired by Alan Pifer and directed by D. Lydia Bronte. They began to familiarize themselves with the literature of the field, to build a small library and to acquaint themselves with the leading scholars in the field.
Beginning in February 1983, the project sponsored a series of Conferences dealing with the economic, political, social and ethical implications of the Aging American Society. These Conferences also dealt with particular segments of the American Society, such as women, Blacks and Hispanics.
In November of 1983 discussions began with the American Academy of Arts and Sciences for publication of a Collection of essays on aging in an issue of their journal Daedalus. For the remainder of 1983 and 1984, the project staff prepared for the book of essays, met with the essay authors in June 1984, convened additional conferences on aging, and visited Sweden, which has one of the oldest populations in the world.
On February 11-14, 1986 the Aging Society Project held its last Conference, in Japan, entitled "Population Aging in the United States and Japan: National and International Implications."
In the Winter 1986 issue of Daedalus, "The Aging Society" was published. This Collection of essays was also issued with additional articles and in a different form by W.W. Norton and Company under the title Our Aging Society: Paradox and Promise on May 19, 1986. Shortly, after the completion of this book the Aging Society Project ended. The records of the project were donated by D. Lydia Bronte to the University of Michigan's Institute of Gerontology. After processing, this material was transferred to the Michigan Historical Collections/Institute of Gerontology's Joint Archives in Gerontology located in the Bentley Historical Library, Ann Arbor, Michigan.
The Aging Society Project of the Carnegie Corporation of New York record group consists of administrative files, largely of project director D. Lydia Bronte, including subject files, name files, publication records, and conference files. The records have been divided into five series: Subject File; Individuals File; Organization File; Book File; and Conference File.
Subjects:
Aging.; Gerontology.; University of Michigan. Institute of Gerontology.
Contributors:
Bronte, Lydia, 1938-2003
- Subject File, 1982-1986
  The Subject File, contained in boxes 1-2, covers the period 1982-1986. It includes correspondence, interviews, budget proposals, speeches, articles, lists and reports concerning administration of the project, and staff activities. Two major; portions of the material are D. Lydia Bronte's survey on aging, which familiarized her with the subject, and Bronte and Alan Pifer's trip to Sweden, where they studies aging in Europe's oldest society. The series is arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Advisory Board Members, June, 1986 (Box 1)
  - Advisory Group Meeting, November 14, 1983 (Box 1)
  - American Association for Higher Education--Interview re Agency Society Project, December, 1984 (Box 1)
  - American Association of Retired Persons--Article re Aging Society Project, February, 1986 (Box 1)
  - Appointments
    - July-September, 1982 (Box 1)
    - October-December, 1982 (Box 1)
    - 1983-1986 (Box 1)
  - Bronte, Lydia
    - Miscellaneous Notes (Box 1)
    - Survey on Age and Aging, 1982
      - Bibliography (Box 1)
      - Drafts, 4 folders (Box 1)
      - Lists of Individuals Interviewed (Box 1)
      - Notes on Interviews, 5 folders (Box 1)
  - Carnegie Corporation
    - Agency Society Project Proposal
      - October, 1982 (Box 1)
      - September, 1983 (Box 1)
      - September, 1984 (Box 1)
      - July, 1985 (Box 1)
      - July, 1986 (Box 1)
    - Council on Healthy Adolescent Development (Box 1)
    - Education and Economic Growth Conference, February 2, 1983 (Box 1)
    - Memoranda, 1982-1983 (Box 1)
    - Program Statements, February 1, 1984 (Box 1)
    - Staff Seminars, January, 1985 (Box 1)
    - Text for Annual Report, 1986 (Box 1)
  - Central Maine Area Agency on Aging--Award to Lydia Bronte, October, 1986 (Box 1)
  - Congressional Hearings on Aging, September, 1986 (Box 1)
  - Fertility/Children, 1983-1985 (Box 1)
  - Foundations with an Interest in Aging, 1982-1983 (Box 1)
  - Future Goals, July, 1983 (Box 1)
  - Health Education Project Advisory Board, 1983 (Box 1)
  - Life Support Ethics, undated, 1984; 1986 (Box 1)
  - Medicare DRG Payments, 1984 (Box 1)
  - New York Regional Association of Grantmakers Article re Conference on Public Policy Implications of an Aging Society, 1983 (Box 1)
  - Office Organization, April, 1986 (Box 1)
  - Office Space Rental, 1982 (Box 1)
  - Photographs (Box 1)
  - Pifer, Alan and Lydia Bronte-Resumes (Box 1)
  - Pifer, Alan-Articles
    - New York Times Op-Ed Piece, February, 1984 (Box 1)
    - Planning for a Productive Third Quarter of Life, December, 1984 (Box 1)
    - Washington Post Outlook Section, June, 1986 (Box 1)
  - Pifer, Alan-Speeches
    - The Politics of Austerity, 1981 (Box 2)
    - The Trends of the, 1980s; April 2, 1981 (Box 2)
    - Children-A Rational Resource, October 29, 1982 (Box 2)
    - Coping With the Aging Society, March 7, 1983 (Box 2)
    - The Commitment to Social Progress in an Aging Society (Box 2)
    - March 14, 1983, 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Our Aging Society, February 26, 1986 (Box 2)
    - Commencement Address at Millsaps College, May 11, 1986 (Box 2)
  - Population Statistics (Box 2)
  - Project Brochure (Box 2)
  - Project Description, 1983 (Box 2)
  - Proposed Television Series, 1984 (Box 2)
  - Proposed Television Spots on the Aging Society, 1986 (Box 2)
  - Retirement Trends (Box 2)
  - Staff Meeting, June 17, 1986 (Box 2)
  - Swedish Trip, 1984
    - Arbetslivscentrum (Box 2)
    - Correspondence (Box 2)
    - General (Box 2)
    - National Board of Health and Welfare (Box 2)
    - Persson, Gorain Articles (Box 2)
    - Svanborg, Alvar Notes and Articles, 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Swedish Institute for Social Research (Box 2)
    - Swedish Planning and Rationalization Institute, 4 folders (Box 2)
  - United States-Mexican Relations Project, 1979; 1983; 1984; 2 folders (Box 2)
- Individuals File, 1982-1986
  The Individuals File, boxes 3-5, includes correspondence, conference presentations and articles by leaders in the field of aging. This material covers the period 1982-1986. It is arranged alphabetically by author or correspondent.
  - Achenba-Lun, W. Andrew, 1979; 1982-1986 (Box 3)
  - Anderson, Melody M., 1986 (Box 3)
  - Arthurs, Alberta, 1986 (Box 3)
  - Atchley, Robert C., 1984 (Box 3)
  - Avorn, Jerry, 1984; 1985 (Box 3)
  - Axford, Roger W., 1984-1985 (Box 3)
  - Baker, John, 1986 (Box 3)
  - Baldwin, Jean S., 1985; 1986 (Box 3)
  - Bane, Mary Jo, 1983 (Box 3)
  - Barkanic, Steve, 1983 (Box 3)
  - Barocas, Victor S., 1983 (Box 3)
  - Benedict, Stephen, 1985; 1986 (Box 3)
  - Birren, James E., 1982-1986; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Bonkam, George W., 1986 (Box 3)
  - Borthwick, Thomas, 1983 (Box 3)
  - Bove, Joyce, 1984 (Box 3)
  - Brennan, Eamon, 1984 (Box 3)
  - Brennan, Lorna, 1983 (Box 3)
  - Brim, Orville G., 1983-1984 (Box 3)
  - Brooks, Robert E., 1985-1986 (Box 3)
  - Brosnan, Cyril, 1986 (Box 3)
  - Brummel, Steven W., 1984 (Box 3)
  - Bruner, Rosemary, 1984 (Box 3)
  - Buchanan, Constance H., 1985 (Box 3)
  - Buchanan, Joan, 1984 (Box 3)
  - Butler, Robert N., 1982-1983; 1985-1986 (Box 3)
  - Callahan, Daniel, 1983; 1985 (Box 3)
  - Caplan, Arthur L., 1983 (Box 3)
  - Capron, Alexander M., 1983 (Box 3)
  - Carlson, Elliot, 1985 (Box 3)
  - Casey, Cathleen, 1985 (Box 3)
  - Cernik, Anton J., 1984 (Box 3)
  - Chomitz, Kenneth M., 1985 (Box 3)
  - Clements, William, 1983 (Box 3)
  - Coclet, Marie Jo, 1983 (Box 3)
  - Cole, Janet and Jan Oxenberg, 1984-1985 (Box 3)
  - Cole, Thomas R., undated (Box 3)
  - Coleman, Peter, 1984; 1985 (Box 3)
  - Coleman, Robert, 1984 (Box 3)
  - Condon, John, undated (Box 3)
  - Cornman, John M., 1986 (Box 3)
  - Cross, Trudy, 1982 (Box 3)
  - Crystal, John C., 1984 (Box 3)
  - Crystal, Stephen, undated (Box 3)
  - Davis, Karen, 1983 (Box 3)
  - Deagle, Edwin A., Jr., 1983; 1984 (Box 3)
  - Dean, Marita M., 1986 (Box 3)
  - Downey, Thomas J., 1981; 1982; 1983 (Box 3)
  - Drake, Merle, 1985-1986 (Box 3)
  - Dubrovsky, Gertrude, 1985-1986 (Box 3)
  - Dumpson, James R., 1985 (Box 3)
  - Dychtwald, Ken, 1983 (Box 3)
  - Eckert, Kevin, 1982 (Box 3)
  - Edgerton, Russ, 1986 (Box 3)
  - Elms, Roslyn, 1985; 1986 (Box 3)
  - Eppley, George, 1984 (Box 3)
  - Estes, Carroll L., 1982-1983 (Box 3)
  - Eustis, Nancy, 1984 (Box 3)
  - Fahey, Charles J., 1982; 1983 (Box 3)
  - Ferris, William, 1984 (Box 3)
  - Foner, Nancy, 1982 (Box 3)
  - Fox, Renee C., 1983 (Box 3)
  - Franklin, Joan S., 1986 (Box 3)
  - Friday, William, 1985; 1986 (Box 3)
  - Friis, Henning, 1985 (Box 3)
  - Frisch, Dennis, 1986 (Box 3)
  - Fuchs, Victor R., 1983 (Box 3)
  - Fullerton, Howard, 1983 (Box 3)
  - Gardner, John, 1984 (Box 3)
  - Gibson, Robert D., undated, 1984; 1985 (Box 3)
  - Gibson, Rose, 1985 (Box 3)
  - Goggin, Jacqueline A., 1985-1986 (Box 3)
  - Golant, Stephen Myles, 1983-1984; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Goldman, Connie, 1984-1985 (Box 3)
  - Gollub, James, 1985 (Box 3)
  - Goslin, David A., 1985 (Box 3)
  - Gould, Jane S., 1986 (Box 3)
  - Greenhouse, Steven, 1986 (Box 3)
  - Gross, Ronald, 1983 (Box 3)
  - Guggenheim, Charles, 1985 (Box 3)
  - Hagestaad, Gunnhild O., 1984-1985 (Box 3)
  - Halper, Thomas, undated (Box 3)
  - Handel, Leo A., 1986 (Box 3)
  - Hardison, O.B., Jr., 1982 (Box 3)
  - Hardman, Craig, 1983 (Box 3)
  - Hareven, Tamara K., 1976; 1978; 1981 (Box 3)
  - Hargrave, Sarah F., 1982 (Box 3)
  - Harrison, James, 1984 (Box 3)
  - Hauser, Philip M. (Box 3)
  - Heaton, Kenneth L., 1984-1986 (Box 4)
  - Held, Scottie, 1985 (Box 4)
  - Hepworth, Janice C., 1985 (Box 4)
  - Higgins, H. Scott, 1982 (Box 4)
  - Hill, Herbert, 1978; 1979 (Box 4)
  - Hofland, Brian, 1985 (Box 4)
  - Holden, Constance, 1983 (Box 4)
  - Holloway, Joseph, 1985 (Box 4)
  - Horowitz, Janice, 1980s (Box 4)
  - Hoyt, Mary Finch, 1986 (Box 4)
  - Hubbard, Lynda, 1984 (Box 4)
  - Huntington, Patricia, 1982; 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Irwin, Kenneth, 1986 (Box 4)
  - Jeffery, Margot, 1985 (Box 4)
  - Jessup, Philip S., 1983 (Box 4)
  - Johnson, Malcolm L., 1984; 1985; 1986 (Box 4)
  - Jones, Edith Irby, 1986 (Box 4)
  - Jordan, Deanna, 1986 (Box 4)
  - Kahn, Alfred J., 1983; 1984 (Box 4)
  - Kahn, Robert L., 1983 (Box 4)
  - Keating, Pamela J., 1983 (Box 4)
  - Kendig, Hal L., 1986 (Box 4)
  - Keys, Martha, 1984 (Box 4)
  - Kieffer, Jarold A., 1983 (Box 4)
  - King, Patricia, 1983; 1985 (Box 4)
  - Kingson, Eric, 1985 (Box 4)
  - Kip, Richard D., 1983 (Box 4)
  - Krueger, Mark, 1986 (Box 4)
  - Lacy, Suzanne, 1984 (Box 4)
  - Lafe, William, 1984 (Box 4)
  - Lampman, Robert J., 1984 (Box 4)
  - Lane, Gloria, 1983 (Box 4)
  - Lederberg, Joshua, 1984 (Box 4)
  - Leduc, Robert F., 1985 (Box 4)
  - Lewis, Myrna, 1983; 1985 (Box 4)
  - Lorentz, Elizabeth, 1983-1985 (Box 4)
  - MacKay, Buddy, 1983 (Box 4)
  - Magat, Richard, 1985 (Box 4)
  - Marchese, Ted, 1984 (Box 4)
  - Markowitz, Nancy, 1984 (Box 4)
  - Mathews, David, 1986 (Box 4)
  - Matson, Peter, 1984 (Box 4)
  - McCallum, David, 1982; 1985 (Box 4)
  - McCallum, John, 1985 (Box 4)
  - McConnell, Stephen R., 1985 (Box 4)
  - McLaughlin, Joseph J., 1983 (Box 4)
  - Melville, Keith, 1983 (Box 4)
  - Menken, Jane, 1985 (Box 4)
  - Moberg, David 0., 1983 (Box 4)
  - Moody, Harry R. (Rick), 1982-1986; 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Morrisett, Mary, 1983 (Box 4)
  - Morrison, Barbara J., 1985 (Box 4)
  - Morrison, Malcolm H., 1983; 1985-1986 (Box 4)
  - Mulkey, Young Jay, 1983 (Box 4)
  - Murdock, John A., 1984 (Box 4)
  - Myers, Albert M., 1986 (Box 4)
  - Plyers, George C., 1983 (Box 4)
  - Nelson, John K., 1982 (Box 4)
  - Neugarten, Bernice L., 1981; 1982-1986; 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Neuharth, Dan, 1985 (Box 4)
  - Nichols, Rodney, 1984 (Box 4)
  - Pabst, Kathleen M., 1986 (Box 4)
  - Pace, Frank, 1983 (Box 4)
  - Palmer, John L., 1984; 1985-1986 (Box 4)
  - Perry, Daniel, 1983; 1985 (Box 4)
  - Peterson, David A., 1983 (Box 4)
  - Philibert, Michael, 1982; 1983 (Box 4)
  - Polisar, Patti, 1986 (Box 4)
  - Preston, Samuel H. (Box 4)
  - Rabin, David L., 1982; 1983; 1984 (Box 4)
  - Rae, Lynda, 1984; 1985 (Box 4)
  - Raymond, Jack, 1983 (Box 4)
  - Reilly, James E., 1984 (Box 4)
  - Reynolds, Clark, 1984 (Box 4)
  - Richman, Harold, 1984 (Box 4)
  - Riley, Matilda White and John W. Riley, 1982-1986; 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Robbin, Alexandra, 1984 (Box 5)
  - Rodale, Robert, 1986 (Box 5)
  - Roll, Win, 1986 (Box 5)
  - Root, Lawrence S., 1985 (Box 5)
  - Rosenbaum, Ruth, 1986 (Box 5)
  - Rossi, Alice S., 1983-1985 (Box 5)
  - Russell, Rose, 1982 (Box 5)
  - Salk, Lee, 1982 (Box 5)
  - Salwen, Judy, 1984 (Box 5)
  - Sartin, Nancy, 1985 (Box 5)
  - Schearer, S. Bruce, 1986 (Box 5)
  - Schechter, Mal, 1982 (Box 5)
  - Scheider, Edward, 1985 (Box 5)
  - Schloss, Simone L., 1984; 1985 (Box 5)
  - Sclove, Richard E., 1985 (Box 5)
  - Scull, Andrew, 1983 (Box 5)
  - Sears, Phyllis, 1984 (Box 5)
  - Sheppard, Harold L., 1983 (Box 5)
  - Shulman, Norm, 1983 (Box 5)
  - Siegel, Jacob S., undated; 1982; 1984-1986; 3 folders (Box 5)
  - Simpson, Donald F., 1982 (Box 5)
  - Smith, M. Brewster, 1982-1983 (Box 5)
  - Somers, Anne R., 1983 (Box 5)
  - Sommerstein, Judith C., 1985 (Box 5)
  - Spicker, Stuart F., 1982 (Box 5)
  - Starr, Paul, 1984 (Box 5)
  - Steiner, Gilbert, 1982 (Box 5)
  - Stern, Leonard, 1984 (Box 5)
  - Stetson, Charles P., 1985 (Box 5)
  - Stewman, Shelby, 1984 (Box 5)
  - Storey, James, 1982; 1983 (Box 5)
  - Streib, Gordon F., 1983; 1986 (Box 5)
  - Teitelbaum, Michael S., 1982; 1984-1986 (Box 5)
  - Thane, P.M., 1986 (Box 5)
  - Thayer, Frederick C., 1984 (Box 5)
  - Thomas, Lewis, 1986 (Box 5)
  - Thompson, Wendy A., 1985; 1986 (Box 5)
  - Tilson, David, 1983 (Box 5)
  - Torres-Gil, Fernando, 1984-1986 (Box 5)
  - Tropman, John E., 1983 (Box 5)
  - Tucker, Karen and Jane Murphy, 1985 (Box 5)
  - Turesky, Stanley F., 1985; 1986 (Box 5)
  - Van Tassel, David D., 1982; 1983 (Box 5)
  - Vinyard, Dale, 1983; 1984 (Box 5)
  - Walker, James Perry, 1985; 1986 (Box 5)
  - Ward, Debbie, 1985 (Box 5)
  - Warren, Kenneth S., 1983 (Box 5)
  - Warshaw, Leon, 1986 (Box 5)
  - Wetele, Terry, 1985 (Box 5)
  - Wiedinmyer, Pat, 1985 (Box 5)
  - Wilber, Kate, 1984 (Box 5)
  - Williams, Robin M., 1983 (Box 5)
  - Woodward, Kathleen, 1982; 1983; 1984; 1985 (Box 5)
  - Worthy, Edmund H., 1982; 1983 (Box 5)
  - Wynne, Edward A., 1984; 1985 (Box 5)
  - Yankelovich, Daniel, 1985 (Box 5)
  - Youssef, Fathi S., 1983 (Box 5)
  - Zimmer, Anna H., 1982 (Box 5)
- Organizations File, 1982-1986
  The Organization File, boxes 6-10, covers the period 1982-1986. The material includes correspondence, speeches and publications from and by organizations in the aging field, such as the American Association for the Advancement of Science, the Brookdale Center, Council on Foundations, Gerontological Society of America, and the National Council on Aging. This material is arranged alphabetically by title of organization.
  - Academy of Independent Scholars, 1980; 1983; 1984; 1986; 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Academy of Senior Professionals, 1982-1984; 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Aging Research Policy Council, undated (Box 6)
  - Aluminum Association, 1984; 1985 (Box 6)
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science Annual Meeting
    - 1984, 3 folders (Box 6)
    - 1985, 5 folders (Box 6)
    - Bronte Speech, "The Third Quarter of Life", 1985 (Box 6)
  - American Association of Retired Persons, 1985; 1986 (Box 6)
  - American Council on Life Insurance, 1982; 1983 (Box 6)
  - American health Magazine's Mind, Body Weekend, 1985 (Box 6)
  - American Institute for Character Education, 1983; 1984; 1985 (Box 6)
  - Association of Arts Administration Educators, Annual Meeting--Bronte speech, 1985 (Box 6)
  - Biopsychological Institute for Education, 1985 (Box 6)
  - Brandeis University-Heller School, 1982 (Box 6)
  - Brookdale Center
    - Generational Equity Luncheon, May 16, 1986 (Box 6)
    - Human Values and Aging Newsletter
      - 1981-1982 (Box 6)
      - 1983-1984 (Box 6)
      - 1985-1986 (Box 6)
    - Medical Conference on Aging, 1984 (Box 6)
    - Newsletter, 1981-1986 (Box 6)
    - White House Conference on Aging Miniconference, 1981 (Box 6)
  - Broome County Child Development Council (Box 6)
  - Commonwealth Fund, 1982 (Box 6)
  - Community Council of Greater New York
    - Ad hoc Social Security Committee, 1980; 1982; 2 folders (Box 6)
    - Medicare Task Force, 1984 (Box 6)
  - Community Service Society of New York, 1979-1982; 3 folders (Box 7)
  - Conference Board, undated; 1983 (Box 7)
  - Council of Better Business Bureaus, 1983 (Box 7)
  - Council on Foundations
    - Annual Conference, 1984; 2 folders (Box 7)
    - Annual Conference, 1985; 5 folders (Box 7)
      (Bronte Moderated session)
  - Delaware Senior Consultants, 1985 (Box 7)
  - Displaced Homemakers Network, undated (Box 7)
  - East-West Center Meeting on Aging, November 11-14, 1985 (Box 7)
  - Eastern Sociological Society, 1983; 1984 (Box 7)
  - Elvirita Lewis Foundation, 1985-1986; 2 folders (Box 7)
  - Employee Benefit Research Institute, 1985 (Box 7)
  - Ethel Percy Andrus Gerontology Center-Age, Health and Productivity Seminar, 1983; 2 folders (Box 7)
  - Family Service of America, 1984; 1985 (Box 7)
  - Federal Senior Community Service Employment Program, 1984 (Box 7)
  - Foundation for Child Development, 1984 (Box 7)
  - Foundation for Health Services Research-Health Promotion and Disease Prevention for Children and the Elderly Conference, October 9-11, 1983; 3 folders (Box 7)
  - Gerontological Society of America
    - Annual Meeting
      - 1982, 3 folders (Box 7)
      - 1983, 2 folders (Box 7)
      - 1984, 2 folders (Box 8)
      - 1985, 2 folders (Box 8)
      - 1986 (Box 8)
    - General, undated (Box 8)
    - Report on "The Common Stake in Social Policy,", 1985; 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Grantmakers in Aging
    - Annual Meeting
      - 1984, 3 folders (Box 8)
      - 1986 (Box 8)
    - General, 1982-1986 (Box 8)
    - Planning Meeting, July 2, 1986 (Box 8)
  - Grantmakers in Health, 1983; 1984 (Box 8)
  - Gray Panthers, 1984 (Box 8)
  - Hampshire College Emeritus Program, 1982 (Box 8)
  - Harvard University Working Group on Health Policy and Aging, 1982 (Box 8)
  - Hastings Center Meetings, 1981-1985; 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Institute for Applied Economics, 1983 (Box 8)
  - Institute for the Puerto Rican/Hispanic Elderly, 1981; 1982 (Box 8)
  - International Congress of Gerontology, 1985 (Box 8)
  - International Executive Service Corps, 1983 (Box 8)
  - Life Span Services, 1985 (Box 8)
  - Manpower Demonstration Research Corporation, 1981; 1982 (Box 8)
  - MIT and Harvard Joint Center for Urban Studies, 1983 (Box 8)
  - Modern Maturity Television Series, 1985 (Box 8)
  - National Academy of Sciences-Institute of Medicine Annual Meeting, 1982 (Box 8)
  - National Clearinghouse on Aging, 1982 (Box 8)
  - National Coalition of Hispanic Mental Health and Human Services Organizations, 1983; 1984 (Box 8)
  - National Coalition on Older Women's Issues, 1983; 2 folders (Box 8)
  - National Commission for Employment Policy, 1982; 1983 (Box 8)
  - National Council on the Aging
    - Annual Meeting
      - 1984 (Box 9)
      - 1985, 2 folders (Box 9)
      - 1986, 4 folders (Box 9)
    - General, 1978; 1980; 1982-1985 (Box 9)
    - Symposium on the Arts, the Humanities and Older Americans, 1981; 2 folders (Box 9)
  - National Education Association, 1986 (Box 9)
  - National Institute on Aging, 1981; 1982; 1984 (Box 9)
  - National Network of Grantmakers, 1983; 1986 (Box 9)
  - National Organization of Women, 1986 (Box 9)
  - National Policy Center on Employment and Retirement-Seminar on Age, Health and Productivity, 1983 (Box 9)
  - NATO Conference on Technology and Aging, August 22-26, 1983; 2 folders (Box 9)
  - New Age, Inc., 1985 (Box 9)
  - New York Academy of Sciences, 1983; 1984; 1985 (Box 9)
  - New York City Department for the Aging, 1983; 1985 (Box 9)
  - New York Hospital-Cornell Medical Center-Women's Health Symposium, 1983; 1985 (Box 9)
  - New York Regional Association of Grantmakers, 1982-1986; 2 folders (Box 9)
  - New York State Coalition of the Concerned for Older Americans, 1983 (Box 9)
  - New York State Conference on Midlife and Older Women, October 24-25, 1983; 4 folders (Box 9)
  - New York State Office for the Aging, 1982; 1985 (Box 9)
  - Northwest Area Foundation, 1982; 1986 (Box 9)
  - Office of Technology Assessment
    - General, undated; 1983 (Box 10)
    - Technology and Aging Advisory Panel, 1982; 1983 (Box 10)
    - Workshop on "The Impact of Technology on Long-Term Care, February 16-18, 1983; 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Older Women's League
    - General, 1982; 2 folders (Box 10)
    - OWL Observer, 1982-1986; 3 folders (Box 10)
  - Resources for Older Women, 1982-1985 (Box 10)
  - Retirement Research Foundation, 1979-1983 (Box 10)
  - Rockefeller University Aging Project, 1982; 1983 (Box 10)
  - Smithsonian Institution, 1986 (Box 10)
  - Teachers' Insurance and Annuity Association, 1985; 1986 (Box 10)
  - United Nations International Conference on Population, 1984 (Box 10)
  - U.S. Senate Special Committee on Aging, 1982; 1985 (Box 10)
  - V.I.E., 1983; 1984 (Box 10)
  - Villers Foundation, 1983-1985; 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Washington Business Group on Health, 1983; 1985 (Box 10)
  - Women and Foundations Corporate Philanthropy, 1980-1987; 4 folders (Box 10)
  - Women's Research and Education Institute, 1982; 1983; 1985; 1986 (Box 10)
  - Woods Hole Conference on Demographic Change and the Well-Being of Children and the Elderly, September 5-7, 1985; 5 folders (Box 10)
  - Work in America Institute, 1985 (Box 10)
  - Yale Symposium on Social Security, November 8-9, 1985 (Box 10)
- Book File
  The Book File, boxes 11-15, contains meeting summaries and transcripts, chapter drafts, correspondence, articles and book reviews. These papers concern advisory committee meetings, author conferences, drafts of individual chapters, the selection of a book agent and publisher, and book publicity. This file is arranged alphabetically by topic.
  - Advisory Committee
    - Meeting, November, 1983 (Box 11)
    - General, November, 1983-January, 1984 (Box 11)
    - Suggestions for Book Authors, February, 1984 (Box 11)
  - Audio Cassette Companies, April-October, 1986 (Box 11)
  - Authors Conference
    - June 11, 1984
      - General (Box 11)
      - Notes (Box 11)